### **RUDY HUAYHUA BRAVO**

859 Zorritos Street, Breña Lima - Peru Mobile 51 955555610 Email: r.huayhua@pucp.pe

### SUMMARY

Bachelor of Science with major in Electronic Engineering from Pontifical Catholic University of Peru. Self-starter, willingness to work both independently and as a team member with over 5 years of technical experience in IT development projects. Ability to learn new technologies and develop a deep understandig of new systems. Known for strong analytical skills that has let me to improve the efficiency of IT systems.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNIBANCA

Apr 2015 – Present

### Software Engineer

- Configured transaction processing platform ESP-Link for payments business according with business logic to meet the specific requirements of customers.
- Configured new networks and host interfaces for introduction of new products and services.
- Developed interfaces for online messages to integrate with other internal or external systems like Visa, MasterCard, Pulse and DCI.
- Developed and maintained shell scripts for network administration.
- Provided technical expertise to new staff for payment applications and clarified business requirements and technical considerations to service partners.
- Coordinated the deployment of patches, upgrades and other changes needed to meet technical requirements such as EMV compliance, e-commerce, surcharge commission and fast funds.
- Assessed changes, new services and configurations to ensure impacts are properly managed.
- Responsible for preparing technical documentation, user manuals and procedures.
- Responsible for troubleshooting and debugging to determine system errors to increase transaction approval rates.

**VIETTEL PERU** 

Mar 2014 - Mar 2015

# Software Engineer

- Responsible for managing ZTE Online Charging System solution.
- Registered new services and products according with business requirements.
- Configured tariff packages depending on customer needs and special promotions.
- Provided reports on a regular daily basis to evaluate KPI.
- Supported NOC team, responsible for troubleshooting customer complaints.

## GDP SUPERGROUP

Mar - Sep 2013

#### Software Developer

- Cooperated to create and maintain libraries in HTML5 for online casino games.
- Assessed web applications to meet customer requirements.
- Created 2D animation in ActionScript 3.0 for new games.

#### PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF PERU

Mar 2010 - Dec 2012

Teaching Assistant

Courses: Programming Languages, Digital Circuits, Discrete-Time Signals and Systems, Digital Signal Processing, Series and Transforms.

### PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF PERU

Mar - Dec 2011

Research Assistant

- Implemented algorithms in MATLAB to perform compressive sensing technique in image and signal processing.
- Programmed an A/D converter in C language to acquire microphone signals for radar signal processing.

# MARINE INSTITUTE OF PERU – IMARPE

Jun - Sep 2009

Intern

- Developed a program in MATLAB to monitor ships location based on satellite images.
- Developed a program in MATLAB to report wind direction and speed in the Peruvian coast based on satellite data provided by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration NOAA.

### **EDUCATION**

#### PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF PERU

Mar 2005 - Dec 2009

Bachelor of Science with major in Electronic Engineering (Upper fifth)

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Technical analysis skills across payment transaction systems.
- Experience in SQL Database.
- Knowledge of security modules such as HSM for switching applications.
- Good understanding of different transaction message types and standards like ISO8583.
- Strong troubleshooting skills to resolve incidents.
- Shell scripting.
- Familiarity with Visa, MasterCard, Pulse and DCI.
- Experience in payment system development projects.
- Knowledge and hands-on experience with ATM.

**LANGUAGES** English: B2 level

Spanish: 1st language

**COMPUTING** C, C++, MATLAB, Python,

R, Bash scripting, PL/SQL

### **PERSONAL DATA**

Place and date of birth:

Lima-Peru, 24 February 1988